<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-07-03T23:14:17+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Turtle</title><subtitle>Turtle</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Becoming Productive</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/procrastinate-effectively" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Becoming Productive" /><published>2021-06-10T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-06-10T12:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/procrastinate-effectively</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/procrastinate-effectively">&lt;h1 id=&quot;becoming-productive&quot;&gt;Becoming Productive&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building up strong habits is key for building up long-term success!🥇 Only through performing tasks frequently we can expect to become any better. However, finding the motivation to stand up and exercising instead of relaxing is challenging. I like to share some tips building up the discipline needed to accomplish our goals.😉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;setting-a-purpose&quot;&gt;Setting a Purpose&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may seen as an obvious points, but we tend to do things we like more often than things we dislike. We may enjoy playing video games while feeling frustrated learning for an important exam. While the former provides instant gratification, the later can be seen as one of many stepping stones towards a very fulfilling future. That said, the vague idea of pleasant future does little to motivate our brains to stay focused on a daunting, tedious exercise preparing us for that exam. What our brains want is instant joy, pleasant experiences, now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, one path of tackling the issue is to trick our brains into the believe that what we are going to learn in preparation of the exam is inline with a greater purpose. So, instead of pondering over complicated formula and deciding that Social Media or the latest news are more satisfying, we should imagine ourself what we can achieve using the knowledge we are about acquire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After having established a vivid picture in our minds of what to do with the content of the exam, let’s find out more about techniques helping us to learn more effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;active-recall&quot;&gt;Active Recall&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video games are captivating because the provide constant feedback. You kill an enemy and gain instant reward for doing so. The vast majority of activities considered to be “productive” lack that instand feedback mechanism, thus feeling less rewarding.🤦‍♂️ However, there are ways to make seemingly daunting tasks more enjoyable. Imagine, we try to learn  Spanish by reading text book containing some basic sessions. We will stay focused for half an hour, but ultimately realise that our minds wonder to other topics, because we are pursuing a passive activity. Just reading a book does very little to stimulate our brains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An alternative approach would be to use the concept of Active Recall, which is in essence giving ourselves prompts and producing corresponding answers. Finding answers to specific questions is a much more active process, able to capture our attention for a longer period of time. Active Recall is used in flash card systems, proven to be provide better learning results than passive learning strategies.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jan Schumann</name></author><category term="Productivity" /><summary type="html">Becoming Productive Building up strong habits is key for building up long-term success!🥇 Only through performing tasks frequently we can expect to become any better. However, finding the motivation to stand up and exercising instead of relaxing is challenging. I like to share some tips building up the discipline needed to accomplish our goals.😉 Setting a Purpose It may seen as an obvious points, but we tend to do things we like more often than things we dislike. We may enjoy playing video games while feeling frustrated learning for an important exam. While the former provides instant gratification, the later can be seen as one of many stepping stones towards a very fulfilling future. That said, the vague idea of pleasant future does little to motivate our brains to stay focused on a daunting, tedious exercise preparing us for that exam. What our brains want is instant joy, pleasant experiences, now.</summary></entry></feed>